how's it going guys this is Nick at
bobbend.com and it's that time again
when I get to be a talking head on your
computer screen talking about
supplements and today we're talking
about one of the most common and beloved
supplements in the entire world of
Sports Nutrition and that is the
Pre-Workout caffeine for a workout can
have a tremendous difference not just in
the amount of energy you have but also
your focus your endurance and there's
not just caffeine in these products it's
actually a wide variety of other
ingredients and you've even got
pre-workouts without caffeine in them at
all because these other ingredients
which are nut stimulants can still
improve your workout it's a very very
interesting science and we're going to
get into all of it we're going to talk
about the best pre-workout overall the
best for women the best without caffeine
the strongest pre-workout the one the
most caffeine and many other picks so
make actually you know go anywhere
[Music]
now before I go on I need to make it
clear here for like legal reasons I'm
not a doctor uh I am no medical
professional myself I am a dude who has
tried and reviewed dozens and dozen
dozen dozens probably hundreds of
pre-workers at this point but if you are
considering making any changes to your
supplemental nutrition regimen like
absolutely sudden you go and see your
doctor to get a professional opinion and
make sure that nothing's going to
conflict with your own nutrition your
own lifestyle medications may be taking
and so on now you click on this video
because you want to know what the best
pre-workout is and while I've got a lot
of other stuff to talk about I respect
your time I'm gonna let you know right
now what our number one pick is and it
is huge supplements wrecked it is a very
very legit pre-workout not just because
of all the caffeine it's got also the
type of caffeine it's got two different
kinds so it's going to break down more
slowly give you more sustained energy
but all the other ingredients here are
super legit as well it's got a ton of
ingredients for blood flow and pump like
citrulline it's got plenty of beta in
and hydro just a power beta alanine for
endurance and a lot more it's even got a
bit of salt and air for hydration which
is a super underrated pre-workout
ingredient we get all into that but all
those words I just said citrulline beta
alanine beta in you're probably
wondering what they are and what are
these very common pre-workout
ingredients that aren't caffeine that I
keep talking about well you come to the
right place let's talk about the most
common most researched back pre-workout
ingredients you might want to keep an
eye out for and how much of them you
should be taking all right let's just
quickly cover caffeine as a common
pre-workout ingredient because a lot of
people are unaware of the actual effects
of it and also the correct dosage
caffeine it's not just an eye opener
that gets you out of bed and gets you
moving in the morning it also has very
serious very well researched benefits
for exercise in particular like stuff
like reaction time working memory
perceptual memory power output aerobic
output all these sorts of things they're
very closely linked to caffeine so it's
not just like makes you feel a bit more
energized there are very concrete ways
it can improve a wide variety of
athletic Endeavors content-wise a 12
ounce Starbucks cold brew has about
155mm grams of caffeine in them the
average pre-workout
180 to 200 milligrams of caffeine there
are much much stronger on this list
after that we've got citrulline it is an
amino acid that's found in a lot of
Natural Foods watermelon is one of them
citrulline has links with blood flu
increased blood flow and it's a
precursor for nitric oxide and in
addition to a lot of interesting
implications and interesting research
performed on that for like a pow app and
endurance like endurance in particular
that's also like good for blood pressure
overall something to note about
citrulline is that is often under dosed
all the research on it that's shown like
benefits and studies has a good five six
seven eight nine ten grams of citrulline
you really want to make sure you're
getting at least five grams if you're
wanting to lean on the benefits of
sichling in a pre-workout that's an
important thing to look for beta alanine
is also very very common in pre-workout
the dosage is 1.6 grams at a minimum
often up to 3.2 grams what that is about
is like cardio and endurance life
largely like it increases time to
exhaustion in a fair amount of research
in fact there was one study that found
actually quite a few studies that found
roughly like 2.8 benefit for endurance
athletes and if you're like an athlete
like a high-level athlete like an almost
three percent Improvement is actually
very very significant one thing to note
about it is that it tends to produce
what's called paresthesia which is a
tingling sensation on the skin it's
completely harmless so just be aware of
that it's a bit of alanine it's a
temporary a little tingling sensation on
the skin another one is beta in
anhydrous also called
trimethylglycine it's a most commonly
found in beets like known for being
found in beets also some leafy greens as
well with beta in that has the big
emphasis on power so normally doses of
about two three grams per day often over
the course of a day that's been found to
increase power output in a few studies
uh there's been studies on the back
squat and the bench press specifically
that has seen a kind of measurable
increase in power output there I'll also
mention creatine here creatine is
probably after protein powder the most
common spot supplement out there the
point with creatine is you take about
five grams a day for four weeks or so
and that saturates the muscles and
that's going to give you the benefits of
creatine in the gym some Studies have
found like 12 to 20 increase in power
output it's very impressive it might not
be like 20 for you but definitely like
power output has a very very strong link
with creatine it is one of the most
widely researched squat supplements out
there so all these different components
in pre-workouts they affect workouts in
different ways at different times so
that's why you tend to get a whole bunch
of them all at once the last one I'm
going to mention here is Branch chain
amino acids these are their own category
in sport supplementation there's a whole
lot you can see about uh Banshee amino
acids they're not very common in
pre-workouts because again usually
they're separate products but sometimes
you'll find them thrown in there because
there's some evidence that if you aren't
eating a particularly high protein diet
or if there's been like a long Gap since
your last meal they might help with
muscle retention and potentially help
with like a focus and keeping you some
from losing muscle during your workouts
I've also found myself that if it's been
a long time since my last meal taking
bread chain minuses it can sort of help
to keep the workout going so the best
pre-workout overall is definitely huge
supplements wreck this is an astonishing
product in fact it's so good that we
gave it three Awards we have the best
pre-workout overall the strongest
pre-workout and the best for pumps these
categories are all pretty
self-explanatory I just want to mention
all the other ingredients here that led
to us naming it the best pre-workout
overall because like yes it's got a lot
of caffeine yes has a lot of is linked
to pump as well but I've also put in a
bunch of other ingredients that you very
rarely see in pre-workouts so I've
mentioned like citrulline beta alanine
beta in anhydrous all of those are in
here but in addition to that you've got
Lion's main mushroom so that's like an
adaptogen that has a pretty interesting
links in some studies to uh endurance
and sports performance there's also a
lot of other ingredients here like pink
Himalayan salt sounds very weird I know
but like sodium is a massively
underrated and massively beneficial
component to have before a workout it's
a really good ergogenic Aid athletes
like Stan efforting and Steffi Cohen all
swear by taking some salt before a
workout all the ingredients here are
very very interesting they've gone above
and beyond by getting the most research
back most popular ingredients like
citrulline and betaine and putting a lot
of other interest ingredients it's very
interesting research behind them so very
very impressed by the way wrecked
approaches their pre-workout the
strongest pre-workout as well is what we
name this one the reason for this is not
just because it has
350 milligrams of caffeine but also
because it has different types of
caffeine in it so 250 milligrams of it
is like regular caffeine which is
caffeine anhydrous but also there's 100
milligrams of dye caffeine malates that
is an interesting proprietary product
also called Infinity that's like a
patented name for it and what that is is
caffeine that breaks down more slowly so
instead of getting 350 milligrams of
caffeine immediately absorbing into your
bloodstream the idea is you have the 250
which is already quite a fair amount and
then another 100 is going to break down
more slowly so that's going to be
helpful for endurance workouts longer
term exercise and also just generally
for preventing a big spike and crash in
energy levels so it's a very interesting
approach to the caffeination of this
product then you've got the pumps so a
lot of people are very interested in
getting pumps in their workouts right I
mentioned citrulline earlier and I
mentioned the effects on blood flow and
performance what that also means is
because of the vasodilation it means
that there's just basically more blood
getting to your muscles and more oxygen
getting to the muscles as well that has
benefits for performance but also
potentially on hypertrophy as well
that's muscle gains and this one here
has 8 grams of citrulline per serving so
that is a very impressive amount and
also the beta alanine and bedding
anhydrous other ingredients here also
have links to increase blood flow and
increased pumps as well but citrulline
is the main one here and with eight
grams there's definitely tops the
category so
best pre-worker overall strongest
pre-workout best for pumps huge
supplements wreck really takes them all
home and definitively and decisively so
so we're very comfortable standing
behind that one and we think if you like
that one too let's take a quick right
turn we're going to talk about a
different kind of pre-workout one that
if you can believe it doesn't have any
caffeine at all talking about
Wolverine's pre so this one took home a
fair number of awards here as well but
first we're going to talk about the fact
that it has no caffeine so this is the
best pre-workout without caffeine for a
lot of people asking like a shocking
thing but as mentioned all these other
ingredients I've been talking about none
of these are stimulants right you can
take them later at night they're going
to give you a better workout but they're
not going to keep you up so the
difference between having something that
can improve your performance and
something that's a stimulant so what
wolverine has done here with their prey
is give you all these other ingredients
here you've got the citrulline malate
the beta alanine beta in anhydrous all
these things that we've mentioned but it
does not have any caffeine one thing to
note though is it has some Siberian
ginseng here one gram of it generally
not considered a stimulant it's more of
an adaptogen that can help the body to
manage stress and manage fatigue as
opposed to something that will keep you
awake at night some people that might
have trouble sleeping with it but most
people weren't nonetheless this is a
completely caffeine-free pre-workout and
a great pick for those who want
something that's going to help in the
gym that would have really keep them
very wired another reason why this one
differs a lot from the huge supplements
is that it's all natural right so by
that I mean I'm just saying that it
doesn't have artificial flavors or
sweetness so as opposed to artificial
sweeteners like sucralose and acid
sulfame potassium where Wolverine gets
the flavoring from is from Stevia Leaf
the natural Leaf right there are two
kinds of stevia leaf extract here and
there's also malic acid and citric acid
so totally natural flavoring totally
natural sweeteners and no artificial
coloring either so this is a really good
pick if you're trying to minimize the
artificial stuff which are plenty of
people in the market are trying to do
the third category we gave Wolverine the
edge in is the Pre-Workout for muscle
gain the calories and the workouts those
are of absolute Peak importance for
getting muscle as opposed to what kind
of pre-workout you use however what we
really liked about the ingredients in
sovereigns is that they all tend to lean
themselves to better performance in
workouts and at the end of the day the
best pre-workout for muscle gain is one
that's going to help you to eek out more
reps and get more work done so there's
plenty of beta Allen here a good 3.2
grams it's considered a very high dose
there's better in anhydrous so if your
reps are a little bit lower beta e can
help you with that there's also
carnitine here carnitine is very very
popular in pre-workouts for helping to
limit muscle damage and increase muscle
retention and muscular endurance as well
so there's all sorts of stuff in this
product that can at the end of the day
get you more reps in and getting more
workouts in get you more endurance in
more strength endurance and thereby
helps to increase muscle gain relative
to other pre-workouts so big fan of this
one boy I'm talking a lot I know I know
this is a lot there's a lot of research
here there are 50 million ingredients
you feel like you need to be familiar
with if you're going to find out what a
good pre-workout is or not there's two
pieces of good news number one I deal
with that research for you so you don't
have to do it all but number two there
is a written version of this article
which I would encourage you to check out
if you want to take this in at your own
pace if you want to check out these
studies yourself or get like a closer
look at the kind of research we're
talking about CLD greens broken down so
go to Google and do bar Bend best
pre-workouts it'll come right up and
then you can digest this real slow but
if you want to stick around let's digest
quickly what we really like about this
next pick is that it's sort of a
combination supplement it lets you kind
of hit two birds with one stone combine
a creatine supplement and they
pre-workout supplement the best
pre-workout with creatine is right here
cage muscles pre-caged Elite now
a little bit expensive it's about three
bucks a scoop but like listen 10 grams
of citrulline as I've already mentioned
five grams is a perfectly acceptable
dose you get 10 grams of sizzling in a
dose you have 3.2 grams of beta alanine
again 1.6 grams is perfectly fine you
know what I mean there's also a lot of
caffeine here there's 388 milligrams of
caffeine which is so much you could have
half of that it'll work perfectly fine
you know what I mean so it's expensive
on a past selling basis yes but it's so
partly dark that you can have it and
everything's gonna be fine uh creating
though five fat grams of creatine per
sub so this is a really handy like
double Wham you sort of pre-workout
you're getting your creatine there and
you're also getting all these other
ingredients at very very high doses so
whether you're trying to get a good pump
on or you're going for a really long run
there's everything here that's going to
make your workout work well we also
think this the best we work out for men
a reason why this is ideal for men or
better suited for men number one it's
unbelievably strong in the caffeine
Department if you look at some women
tend to be lower in caffeine because
women tend to weigh less than men right
that's the main difference between these
categories so this is benefited for men
just because it has so much more
caffeine than the average pre-workout
but in addition to that it's got some
interesting ingredients like L-Carnitine
El tartrate guys tend to like kind of
produce or retain less of it as they age
I'll continue it's a pretty good
addition here for physique and for
performance and of course you've also
got all the other things like beta in
anhydrous uh you've also got taurine two
grams which is a good amount that's to
help with focus when you're working out
there's also a good amount of sodium
here 12 of the recommended daily intake
which again is really good for a
pre-workout to have some sodium in there
so this is an unbelievably effective
unbelievably potent pre-workout a little
bit expensive but the price is
definitely Justified given how much
stuff they're cramming into every single
scoop next up we are talking about caged
pre-caged there are two of those who
wanted to give this one the first one is
the best tasting these are the best
tasting pre-workouts this one here is
grape which I have had I think about two
whole tubs of in my lifetime but there's
also crisp apple berry blast pink
lemonade fruit punch and Cherry Bomb and
orange crush as well they're all just so
good pre-workouts I think our companies
have like the most room to play with
flavors and I think that caged did the
best job to get a whole sweet really
delicious flavors and what's interesting
they're naturally flavored they're not
naturally sweetened they have sucralose
in there which is just Splenda but the
flavorings itself are natural which a
lot of people like
the other thing I want to mention the
Caged pre-caged is its best pre-workout
for women as well we're a big fan of
this one female athletes and female
consumers all these sorts of products
tend to do more cardiovascular and
endurance based workouts So to that end
we have in addition to stuff that's
great for cardio like beta alanine which
you mentioned there's also stuff in here
that can increase Focus so what we're
talking about here is taurine and
tyrosine as well there are two kinds of
tyrosine in this it's a vegan friendly
the branched amino acids this has
branched chain amino acids in it the
BCAAs in this particular product they
are vegan they're fermented so that's
pretty cool as well this has the Spectra
orac blend here right which has like
everything from broccoli concentrate to
blackcurrant extract so it's got the
more vegan breasted amino acids it's got
stuff a nice long cardio workouts it's
got stuff for focus and it's got a bunch
of powdered fruits and veggies in it so
those are all reasons thoroughly
gendered reasons the reasons of the less
that we've found that uh women tend to
gravitate a little bit more toward
products like this next up we're going
to talk about transparent Labs which is
a really really cool supplement company
that we cover a lot here at Bob and the
reason being they're very transparent
they give you the precise amount of
everything that they use and on top of
that if you go to their website go like
the product page for this product or any
product you can click on the ingredient
it'll tell you why it's in there and
what studies LED them to do so so that's
really cool so we named lean the best
pre-workout for weight loss and for
thermogenesis which is a turn that you
hear used a lot in the fat burner
supplement world the reason I'm using it
is that lean has an emphasis more of an
emphasis on fat loss and weight loss
than other pre-workouts now the most
important thing is of course the amount
of calories that you eat throughout the
day as I mentioned from muscle gain
earlier it's important to use in a
calorie deficit however an acetyl
L-Carnitine is really interesting
addition here because of all the
research on it as a means for promoting
fat oxidation basically coach you to use
more fat for energy so that's why it is
uh this has more like a fat burning
effect and a fat burning slant to it to
its formulations as opposed to the other
products here so that's the reason why
we named the best pre-workout for weight
loss and for thermogenesis for one it
might help you work out for longer which
is also why we named it the best
pre-workout for running the running
aspect here again two different types of
caffeine helps to promote more endurance
in that respect you've also got some
theobromine in here which has some links
to increase blood flow and endurance in
that regard you've also got black pepper
extract to help this all absorb well and
you've also got beta alanine and you've
got branched chain amino acids so that's
transparent Labs lean it's good for a
whole ton of reasons a very transparent
company and on top of that pearly
naturally flavored and colored and
sweetened if that's important to you as
well next up we're going to talk about a
pre-record that sounds pretty dumb with
my accent Nolly Sports Nutrition very
cool name and we're naming this one
we're giving it a couple of awards but
the best pre-workout for beginners it
keeps things pretty simple and it keeps
things a pretty measured so by that I
mean uh the caffeine in here is just 180
milligrams in addition to that uh
besides the caffeine the citrulline
melee and a good five gram dose you got
better alanine and two and a half grams
you got the caffeine and you've also got
some fresh and amino acids the last
ingredient is that there's some Asian
ginseng root powder and it is
all-natural no artificial flavors not
official sweeteners not too much
caffeine only well researched
ingredients pretty short ingredients
list that's why nollie we think is best
pre-workout for beginners we're also
calling it the best eco-friendly
pre-workout so now he purposely puts her
stuff in these sort of metal paint tins
because they're more likely to get
recycled and on top of that they've also
partnered with the plastic impact
Alliance and sustainable packaging
movement to totally phase out the rest
of their single-use packaging by 2020
five and on top of that the BCAAs are
vegan and without getting too political
about these things you probably know
that uh plant-based products tend to
have a lower carbon footprint than those
that come from animals this is not from
animals so that's a nice little bonus
there as well one more thing I didn't
mention yet actually that this is
certified by NSF for sport and it's a
sport that means they basically do
testing to make sure there's no bad
substances or anything like that in it
especially if you're a competitive
athlete you definitely want to make sure
you're getting something that's been
certified by a buddy like NSF that's a
nice little bonus finale as well next up
says we're talking about vegan
pre-workouts we want to talk about
transparent Labs bulk this is the best
vegan pre-workout this is also a totally
natural product it has no artificial
flavors or sweetness or colors it tastes
really good as well they've got a nice
spread of a spread of flavoring in there
and what's interesting about bulk as
well is that uh it's named bulk because
the idea is that it's a really meant to
help to facilitate muscle building
workouts it's not like it's got like a
whole bunch of testosterone boosters in
it or something like that rather when
you compare it to lean bulk has it just
has more more of the ingredients that
are associated with like erogenic
performance right so while lean has six
grams of citrulline this has eight grams
citrulline while lean has two grams of
beta alanine this is four grams of beta
alanine and so on it really has like
kind of extra strong doses of the most
standard and best research ingredients
in pre-workout actually help you make
the most out of it transparent Labs is
again very well known with their
transparency and that brings a lot of
Peace of Mind to people who absolutely
want to make sure they don't consume any
animal products or any products from
Sudden Origins
thank you
all right so that does it for our list
of the best pre-workouts I wanted to
close out this video to answering a
couple common questions we get about
pre-workouts because it's hard to come
in category in Fitness and in
supplementation one of the questions is
when do I take it like it's called a
pre-workout but like when do I have to
take this course so when you're taking a
pre-workout with caffeine you want to
take it about a half hour before you
work out if there's no caffeine in it
pretty good chance you can just kind of
take it anytime because your body will
maintain those effects of extra
endurance and power and stuff throughout
the day lastly I just want to talk about
things to consider before you buy a
pre-workout right like just just things
to remember
the number one is there's usually plenty
of caffeine in these if you already
drink coffee you know you're unlikely to
be really dramatically negatively
affected by these products but for one
if you are sent to caffeine don't have a
caffeinated pre-workout right but the
caffeine is something to think about
another thing to consider or remember
when getting pre-workouts caffeine is
really the only stimulant here that
you're going to get in these everything
else is not technically a stimulant
there are stimulant like ingredients but
otherwise everything else isn't a
stimulant so if you're really worried
about getting really really wired and
like freaked out by these uh honestly so
long as the caffeine is in line with
what you want to take and that number
can be zero if you want to get a
caffeine free one otherwise you you
should be pretty fine other thing to
keep in mind better alanine is in just
about all of these it does almost always
cause a tingling sensation on the skin
you need to be mindful that is fine it's
completely harmless don't freak out if
that happens and if you don't like that
feeling you want to
dosage is also an important one to
consider we mentioned in the written
article of this as well like what the
normal dosages are these will have good
dosages but yeah just remember that when
you're buying your pre-workout lastly
your diet your overall diet and also
your sleep and everything are going to
have a really big effect on your
performance in the gym as well
That's it man that's our video that's
our video on the best pre-workout again
I just said about a billion different
things if you want to read it at your
own pace and without my annoying accent
you can Google bar band best
pre-workouts otherwise stick around and
I'll see you for the next video
[Music]
thank you